<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://tbasten.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 13:15:41 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tbasten.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Teams Group Membership</title>
      <link>https://tbasten.github.io/posts/2024/02/microsoft-teams-group-membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 13:15:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tbasten.github.io/posts/2024/02/microsoft-teams-group-membership/</guid>
      <description>The idea Have a tool that can be scheduled or ran on demand that mirrors the membership of an AD group to a Microsoft Teams Team.&#xA;The approach This should be pretty easy. Just need to connect to AD and Microsoft Entra or Microsoft Graph to get a list of all the current members and remove / add users where needed.&#xA;Get the members of the group in AD Export group members and data Get the members of the group in Entra ID Export group members and data Compare the current members in Entra ID against the members of the AD Group Output Users to Add Output Users to remove Remove the users that are in the Entra ID group but not in the AD group Add the users that are not in the Entra ID group but are in the AD group Doing it Initially I will be setting the group details as a hashtable and setup the function that we will be using</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And so it begins</title>
      <link>https://tbasten.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 13:11:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tbasten.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Today marks the first of many failed attempts at documenting a journey I go through. ADHD is something that is a blessing and a curse but with the goal to become a better programmer and technical specialist, I hope this the motivation that I need to keep on going.&#xA;I am going to first tackle a couple of ideas that I have at work to create some tools in PowerShell make our staff&amp;rsquo;s lives a bit easier.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
